Los Angeles Plays Itself is a documentary film directed by Thom Andersen.
From its distinctive neighborhoods to its architectural homes, Los
Angeles has been the backdrop to countless movies.
In this dazzling work, Andersen takes viewers on a whirlwind tour through the metropolis' real and cinematic history, investigating the
myriad stories and legends that have come to define it, and meticulously, judiciously revealing the real city that lives beneath.
Narrator (voice), played by Encke King.
Officer Frank Smith in Dragnet (archive footage), played by Ben Alexander.
Frank Stark in Rebel Without A Cause (archive footage), played by Jim Backus.
Lana Turner in L.A. Confidential (archive footage), played by Brenda Bakke.
Dorothy in Bush Mama (archive footage), played by Barbara O. Jones.
Dr. Clayton Forrester in The War of The Worlds
(archive footage), played by Gene Barry.
Los Angeles Plays Itself is an American essay film by Thom Andersen, finished in
2003, exploring the way Los Angeles has been presented in movies.